<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Domain Driven Design on Victor&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/domain-driven-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Domain Driven Design on Victor&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Victor Martínez</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 03:12:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/domain-driven-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Value Objects in Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/value-objects-in-go-and-other-domain-driven-design-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 03:12:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/value-objects-in-go-and-other-domain-driven-design-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about how to apply some DDD principles in Go in idiomatic and simple ways, and I&amp;rsquo;ve come accross a few patterns I&amp;rsquo;d like to share. Mainly we&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about how to apply the concept of Value Objects in Go in two ways. These are examples of how I apply them in my projects and actually use them so these are not just toy examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Event Sourcing in Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/event-sourcing-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 21:13:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/event-sourcing-in-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently gone into doing CQRS with event sourcing along with DDD (Domain Driven Design) principles. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing it in Go and want to share how I do it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To begin with, I&amp;rsquo;ve researched this topic thoroughly; I&amp;rsquo;ve probably watched and re-watched hundreds of videos and read many posts, articles, and books on it. I am by no means a cqrs/es expert, but I have gained some insight into how to do it. The first thing I want to put out there is that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a framework to do this. Ddd and cqrs/es are best done without a framework getting in the way and instead you should create a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2012/08/13/the-clean-architecture.html&#34;&gt;Clean Architecture&lt;/a&gt; where the framework you choose later on becomes a sort of plugin into your application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
