<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Victor&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://victoramartinez.com/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Victor&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Victor Martínez</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:16:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://victoramartinez.com/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Topics for a Computer Science Undergrad</title>
      <link>https://victoramartinez.com/posts/important-computer-science-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:16:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victoramartinez.com/posts/important-computer-science-concepts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a computer science student, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to have a solid foundation in various topics to succeed in the field. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the most critical topics for a computer science undergrad, in no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;maths&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maths&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;calculus&#34;&gt;Calculus&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Calculus is a fundamental subject that helps understand many computer science concepts, such as optimization, machine learning, and differential equations. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to have a good grasp of limits, derivatives, basic integrals, and multi-variable calculus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Get a Computer Science Degree Fast and Cheaply</title>
      <link>https://victoramartinez.com/posts/how-to-get-a-bscs-efficiently/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victoramartinez.com/posts/how-to-get-a-bscs-efficiently/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You read the title, you&amp;rsquo;re probably thinking &amp;ldquo;that sounds like it&amp;rsquo;ll be a crappy idea&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;that sounds exactly like what I want!&amp;rdquo; For the first person, I hope to convince you that a computer science degree need not take 4 years nor be expensive. For the second, I hope to give you a roadmap to earn an accredited CS degree. But, before I start I want to preface this by saying that I am not advocating you go out to a degree mill and just buy a Diploma from a fake school, I&amp;rsquo;ll only be talking about legal, accredited, and reputable ways to get your degree in under 2 years, even less. I also know that it&amp;rsquo;s possible, because I essentially did it last year. So, without further ado, here&amp;rsquo;s how to get a bachelors degree in computer science fast and cheaply.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accepted to Georgia Tech</title>
      <link>https://victoramartinez.com/posts/accepted-to-gt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 22:16:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victoramartinez.com/posts/accepted-to-gt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back on May 31st, 2024, right as I submitted my last assignment for my capstone course, my last class on my BSCS at WGU, I applied for Georgia Tech’s OMSCS program. In August, days before my graduation ceremony, I heard back that I got accepted into the Spring 2025 cohort of Georgia Tech’s Online Masters of Science in Computer Science and this week I just got my gatech.edu email address.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
